CITY OF B
Nur .
What are you looking at ?
Nothing .
- Let 's go . - Okay .
Right .
- Sir . - Miss .
Can 't we just ride the car ?
Unfortunately , we can 't .
The car can 't get through the bridge .
Let 's go .
We 're here .
- We have arrived . - Right .
- Excuse me . - Please .
Sir , thank you .
DISTRICT OF K
How are you ?
Yes . This is my younger sister .
- Ayu . - Prabu .
And this is her friend .
- Nur . - Hi .
Mr. Prabu is the village head .
He will be the supervisor
of your extracurricular activities .
Okay .
Let 's talk about this in my house .
Let 's go .
This way .
Nur ?
- What 's wrong ? - Nothing .
Why can 't they go ?
Poor Ayu .
She and her friends need to do
the extracurricular activity here .
Please help her .
I beg you , sir .
We come from far away .
We intend to contribute something good
for the local people .
Please consider it , sir .
This is the first time for us as well .
No one has asked
to do the extracurricular activity here .
That 's why we can try it , right , sir ?
We will not be a burden .
Our project will help the people .
Whatever is the problem with this village ,
we will try to solve it .
We want to help the villagers .
This activity will benefit the community .
Do you allow us , sir ?
Ms. Ayu .
Ms. Nur ...
I am going to show you a location
which could be suitable
for your program .
Thank you , sir .
This place used to be
a bathing place for the dancers .
But ...
they don 't exist anymore .
No dancers in this village now .
And then ,
it was used as
a source of water of our village .
But in the last few years ,
the water is drying out .
So , the villagers
have some difficulties getting water .
Because the river
is quite far from here .
We can help , sir .
We will make a plan
to channel the water to this place .
Well ...
Please do your best .
A FEW WEEKS LATER
Ouch ...
I have a flat bottom from sitting for too long .
Is it alright ?
Is it still far away ?
About half an hour away .
Alright .
Might as well go to Bali .
Come on , let 's go . Keep your spirit up !
Ayu ...
Are we walking ?
Damn it , are we riding on motorcycles ?
We 're here ?
Thank you .
Thank you , sir .
- Mr . Prabu . How are you , sir ? - Miss Ayu .
Good . How 's your trip ?
Guys , this is Mr. Prabu .
He 's the village head here .
I 'm Prabu .
- Is this everyone ? - Yes , sir .
- Come . Follow me . - Come on .
My apologies .
Our village is a little behind .
We don 't have electricity yet .
But I hope all of you can adapt .
No worries , sir . I 'm used to it .
Here there 's no electricity .
Where I live , electricity is cut often because we don 't pay the bills .
Relax , sir .
The houses here
don 't have bathrooms .
So , if you want to take a bath ,
the boys can go to the river .
And the girls
can use the one bathroom stall at your work plan site .
What if we need to poop ?
Poop ?
The river isn 't that close from here
so what we do usually is
- we dig a hole in the ground . - Oh dear .
That , I 'm not used to .
Excuse me , sir .
On the way here , I heard the sound of gamelan .
Is there another village nearby ?
Gamelan ?
Yes , sir .
It sounded like a traditional ceremony .
When did you hear it ?
On the way here .
You must have misheard it .
Don 't let it bother you .
Okay ?
Now , let me take you to where you 'll be staying at .
Okay , sir .
Ma 'am ?
Boys . Girls .
This is Mrs. Sundari .
For now
the girls will stay at Mrs. Sundari 's house .
The boys
will stay next door until a bigger place is ready .
- Okay ? - Okay , sir .
Ma 'am . I 'll leave the girls to you .
I can 't say no , can I ?
Let 's go , boys .
I 'll take you next door .
- Thank you , sir . - Nur .
Excuse me , ma 'am .
Thanks , Bima .
I 'll be going , ma 'am .
Thank you , Bima .
Come in .
Come , let 's take a look .
Widya .
Why did you say you heard the sound of gamelan ?
Did you not hear it ?
Think before you speak .
We literally just got here , don 't start with strange questions .
I gave my word that we will behave well .
That 's why he gave his permission for our program here .
If anything happens , I 'll be the one taking the blame .
Ma 'am .
Almost all of the houses here
are made of bamboo weaving .
So , we can hear
everything you say
and see anything you wear .
Well ...
If your program succeeds
this " Sinden " would regain its function
as the source of water for our village .
Sinden ?
Yes . That 's what we call this place .
So , Ms. Ayu
our villagers are ready to help .
Pardon me . What is that ?
Oh that ...
The villagers remain respectful
of the traditions of our ancestors .
That 's one of our ways
to worship the universe
and its inhabitants .
I thought it was for summoning the devil , sir .
Wahyu !
There 's no need to summon
when the devil is already standing in front of me here .
I 'm joking , Mr. Wahyu . Don 't take it to heart .
But you 're accurate , sir .
He is the devil of our campus .
Haunting the place for years .
Graduating indefinitely .
Okay . Come with me .
Let 's go , Mr. Bima .
Nur . What 's wrong ?
Nothing .
This is our burial ground .
What are we ? Stupid ?
What ?
Watch your mouth .
Excuse me , sir .
Why are some gravestones covered by black cloths ?
Nothing special .
That just means they 're
less than 10 years old .
I see .
Nothing else to be said about this graveyard .
- Nur ! - Nur .
Are you okay ?
Ms. Ayu ,
maybe you should go back .
Yes , sir .
It 's okay . I can take Nur .
Let 's go .
Be careful .
Most of the villagers
plant corn .
That 's why every day
they spend most of their time here .
Sir . Where does that go ?
That is the way towards the woods .
That monument marks the boundary
between the village and the woods .
Please ...
do not go near that monument .
All of you cannot pass that boundary
and must stay away from the woods .
Why 's that , sir ?
We call that area ...
Tapak Tilas .
It 's not our territory .
Let 's go .
Widya .
Let 's split into groups for smaller programs .
The first group will be Widya and Wahyu .
Second , Nur and Anton .
Third , Bima and I.
Why don 't we just divide into two groups ?
Widya with us ,
Wahyu with Nur and Anton .
No , Bim .
More effective with just two people in one group .
So we can have three separate groups for three different programs .
Bima said
that he heard a voice from the woods .
So he passed the monument to see where the voice came from
but no one was there .
Didn 't Mr. Prabu tell us not to go into the woods ?
Don 't ask me .
Nur .
Does Bima have a girlfriend ?
Ah so that 's why it 's just you and him in your group .
Have you noticed there isn 't anybody our age here ?
Maybe their children have gone to the big cities .
All of them ? Not even one stays ?
That 's strange .
Excuse me .
- Careful , Nur . - Yeah .
Nur .
Don 't take too long , okay ?
Okay .
Nur ?
You haven 't started ?
Widya ?
Widya !
Nur ?
Widya , open the door !
Widya !
Forgive me , God ...
There is no deity but God ...
Nur ?
Forgive me , God ...
God , I ask for your protection from the cursed devils .
Nur ?
What happened , Nur ?
You did not take a bath ?
Don 't take too long , okay ?
Okay .
Widya ?
- Are you done ? - I am .
Let 's get out of here . Quick .
Here 's the coffee .
For whom is the third cup of coffee ?
Ms. Nur ?
Why come at this hour ?
Come in . Sit down . Here .
Sorry to bother you , sir .
No worries .
Excuse me .
How can I help you ?
There 's something I want to ask you .
This is Mbah Buyut .
He lives on the other side of the village .
But he 's an elder here .
So please don 't hesitate .
You can ask me about anything .
So ...
Ever since I arrived at this village ,
I feel there is something ...
weird .
At first , I thought I was just seeing things .
But ...
Drink the coffee .
It 's not polite to refuse the host .
This coffee is prepared for you .
Sorry , I don 't drink coffee .
Please , just drink it .
Please .
Is it sweet ?
What you saw
is a creature
that rules this place .
He is one
of hundreds that inhabits the village .
The village that not everyone can see .
He 's angry
because of what you brought to this village .
What did I bring ?
She doesn 't know
that you 've been looking after her all this time ?
Ms. Nur .
He has promised
to not bother you anymore .
Don 't worry .
These students are my responsibility .
Widya .
Nur ?
Nur !
Nur , what are you doing ?
Snap out of it , Nur !
Snap out of it !
Nur , please !
Nur , snap out of it !
Hey .
What are you doing , Bima ?
Hey !
Why the hell are you dancing at this hour ?
Get up .
Why the hell are you dancing ?
Widya , hey !
Why were you dancing ?
What is wrong with you ?
Hey !
Who the hell dances this late at night ?
Hey .
That 's enough .
Get inside .
What are you doing out here ?
It 's like she 's possessed .
Come on .
What happened ?
Ladies first .
Is this coffee or herbal medicine ?
It 's so bitter .
Don 't just stare at your coffee .
Come on .
Drink it .
I 'm sorry , Mbah .
I don 't drink coffee .
My stomach can 't take it .
Just one sip .
You are
warm blooded .
Someone like you
is well liked by them .
This
might help to make them stay away .
You can stop worrying now .
Sir ...
Why did only Widya get it ?
- You want it ? - Of course .
Finish the coffee first .
Forget about it . I don 't want it anymore .
Thank you .
Sir .
Why did the coffee taste sweet only to me ?
That black coffee
is usually used as an offering to our ancestors .
Spirits love that coffee .
To them , the coffee tastes sweet .
I 've had that coffee a few times
it 's always bitter .
Maybe
something is following you
and is interested in you .
But you don 't need to worry .
Okay ?
Mbah Buyut is here to help .
Nur , I need to tell you something .
Bima has been acting really strange lately .
I often hear Bima moaning at night .
The weird thing is
I hear a woman moaning too from his room .
You 're talking nonsense , Anton .
I 'm serious , Nur !
I didn 't believe what I heard too at first .
- Until I found offerings in his room ! - Anton .
I 've been friends with Bima for a long time .
I know what kind of person he is .
That 's impossible .
Come with me .
Hey , where are we going ?
See ?
Do you believe me now ?
Please come in .
Come in boys .
Starting tonight
all of you will stay here .
So you won 't bother Mrs. Sundari anymore .
- Okay ? - Thank you , sir .
Thank you , sir .
The boys ' room is over there .
And the girls ' room is over there .
Okay ?
Remember . Behave yourselves . Okay ?
Yes , sir .
Okay .
Then I 'll head home .
Please rest .
- Thank you , sir . - Okay .
Night .
Bima .
I need to talk to you .
Nur , we 're going to look around .
Come on .
Don 't forget to close your eyes if you want to sleep .
Excuse me .
Widya ?
What are you doing ?
What is it ?
Where are the boys ?
In their room .
What is it , Widya ?
What 's wrong ?
- What 's wrong , Widya ? - Calm down . Wait .
- Calm down . - What 's wrong , Widya ?
Calm down . Sit down .
Get some water , now !
What 's going on ?
Come on , Anton .
Here .
Calm down .
Widya .
Widya !
Somebody 's doing black magic on you !
Sorry , Bima . I lost it .
You lost it ?
How could you lose it ?
I asked you to give the " Bangle " to Widya .
Sorry , Bim .
I really forgot where I last put it .
Why are you giving an old bracelet to Widya anyway ?
What 's wrong with you ?
I trusted you with that .
And now you lost it !
I was wrong to trust you .
You don 't understand .
There 's a snake ! A snake !
Come on !
That way ! Let 's go !
What the hell is this ?
Mr. Prabu ! There was a huge snake inside !
But we can 't find it now .
Ms. Ayu .
Was there really a snake in the kitchen ?
I didn 't see any snakes , sir .
What I saw in the kitchen were these men barging inside .
I swear ! I saw a big snake there !
Okay . Listen .
Ms. Nur and Ms. Ayu .
Let 's talk at my house .
The past fews days there have been a few incidents .
Maybe it 's best to end your extracurricular activities now .
Sorry ?
We haven 't finished our programs yet .
What happened earlier was just a misunderstanding .
Ms. Nur , you understand why I 'm saying this , right ?
- Peace be upon you . - And upon you .
What 's up with her ?
Hey , Nur .
What did Mr. Prabu say ?
Where is Widya and Bima ?
Widya 's in the room .
As for Bima , God knows where .
He 's probably busy with his program .
Right .
Every time I pass by their work site , Bima and Ayu are not there .
God forbid they went to Tapak Tilas .
Anton .
How much more time do we need to finish the " Sinden " program ?
Do you want to go home ?
Would the campus let us ?
If they found out , we might not graduate .
Peace be upon you , Bima .
Where were you , Bima ?
Have you prayed today ?
It 's been a while since I saw you pray .
My spiritual life is my own business .
Not yours .
Mind your own .
Hey , Nur .
Don 't you want to ask about my spiritual life ?
Nur ?
- We got everything ? - Yes .
Hey , Widya .
Let 's buy some snacks .
Get some for the others too .
- How many ? - Six please .
Mixed with chili or separate ?
Separate , please .
You don 't look like from around here .
I knew it .
So where are you staying ?
Far from here .
Deep into the woods . A village called ...
Wait .
Into the woods ?
Listen to me . I suggest ...
That you find lodging
to stay for tonight .
Don 't go into the woods at night .
Even the locals here
don 't dare to go into the woods at this hour .
Let alone you two who aren 't from around here .
Strange things might occur .
What about it , Widya ?
Just kidding .
I can 't ask a good girl to spend the night .
Unless she wants to , then I 'm game 100 % percent .
It 's fine . I 'll drive really fast .
All right .
If you must go back tonight
go ahead .
But remember this ...
When you go into the woods
be careful .
Don 't let your thoughts be empty .
- Yes , sir . - And always pray .
If something weird occurs
just ignore it .
- Just keep going . - Yes , sir .
All right . What 's the total ?
Fifteen thousand rupiah .
Hey . Talk to me , Widya .
So I know that you 're still behind me .
Drive faster . It 's already late .
Hey , just imagine if this motorcycle suddenly broke down .
That 'd be the end of us .
In the middle of woods like this , where to find repair shops , right ?
What happened ?
- Don 't joke around , Wahyu ! - I 'm not !
Let me check the gas .
Oh , no .
It 's half full .
What should we do ?
Let 's not stop . Just walk .
Hey , Widya . Wait for me ! What if I see something ? Widya !
Watch your words !
Your big mouth caused this !
Still , wait for me !
You see him too , right ?
Then he 's human . Not a ghost .
Come on .
Your motorcycle broke down ?
Yes , sir .
Could you help us ?
- Thank you very much , sir . - You 're welcome .
Yes , sir .
Just wait at our place .
There 's a party going on .
Yes , sir .
There 's a party ! Come on !
Come on ! A party , Widya ! Come on !
A party !
Eat this .
Control yourself ! We 're not exactly guests here .
- Come on . Let 's leave . - What ?
Leave . Now .
They 're not even done fixing the motorcycle .
Your motorcycle is fixed .
Sir .
But just stay here for a while . Enjoy the food .
Yes , sir .
Thank you , sir . But I think we 'll leave now .
I haven 't finished eating yet .
Then , take some food with you .
- Really ? - Of course .
There you go .
Come on . Hurry up !
Let 's go .
We 're guests here .
We could be banished .
What were you thinking , Bima ?
How could you follow your lust ?
Sorry , Nur .
We made a mistake .
Now I believe what Anton said .
He often hears a woman moaning from your room .
What do you mean , Nur ?
Bima .
Get up !
Where 's everyone else ? I come with gifts .
I thought you two got lost in the woods .
Where 's my snack ?
Our return journey was so exciting ! Unforgettable for sure .
Right , Widya ? Come on , let 's go in .
Let 's eat while I tell you all about it . Come on .
Nur , Ayu , Bima ?
Have I got a story for you !
Why so lifeless ?
Hey .
I know . You all must be starving .
What 's the story , Wahyu ?
Listen . On the way back , in the middle of the woods
our motorcycle suddenly broke down .
But suddenly , an old man helped us .
And he invited me and Widya to a party !
I am so full .
- Is there another village in the woods ? - There is !
Nonsense .
There isn 't !
As far as I know , this is the only village in the middle of the woods .
Mr. Prabu also said the same thing .
Widya .
But it was there , right ?
It was there , right , Widya ?
Widya , nod yes .
Alright . Let 's show them what I bring from the party .
You 'll see we 're not talking nonsense . Where is it ?
You will believe me after .
This isn 't monkey 's meat , right ?
Stop what you 're doing , child .
Widya ?
It 'd be better
for you not to get involved .
Or else
you will pay for it .
I suggest you
to stay out of it .
Stay out of what ?
You don 't need to know .
I respect
who is behind you right now .
But I wouldn 't hesitate
to hurt you
if you got involved .
Do you understand , child ?
Bima ?
Bima .
Time for morning prayer .
I made a mistake , Nur .
I had no choice .
Did you really , Bima ?
I swear to God ,
I just realized it now .
Don 't include God 's name in your mistake .
That night ...
I had a dream .
It felt so real .
Widya .
Widya !
She won 't be able to escape
from the snake .
Who are you ?
Call me Dawuh .
Your friend
is ensnared in the ancient ritual of this village .
I can help her .
If you
do everything I tell you .
What do I have to do ?
Go to Tapak Tilas .
In the hut near the gamelan hall
you will find this Bangle .
Give it to your friend
for her protection .
This is the only way
to save her .
And every night
you have to meet me .
I will look after your friend .
And if you do everything I say
you will get what you want .
Anything you want .
That 's my promise .
Oh , my God .
She 's a jinn !
How could you believe a jinn ?
Nur .
I swear to God !
At that time ,
I only thought about Widya .
Your lust took control of you , Bima .
Seek forgiveness .
Forgive me , God .
I caught you with Ayu yesterday .
Who was the woman Anton heard in your room ?
I only remember
Dawuh 's temptations
haunt me every night .
Where is the Bangle now ?
I don 't know , Nur .
I 'm afraid
Widya is in danger .
I also saw Widya with a snake in my dream .
This must be a sign , Bima .
I 'm prepared to pay the price .
Nur ?
Ayu ?
Anton ?
Bima ?
Nur ?
What are you doing ?
Pretty child .
You like it here ?
So ?
Have you met Badarawuhi ?
Why are you crying , pretty child ?
Please don 't cry .
It 's not good to cry .
Even that handsome boy
has met Badarawuhi .
You don 't know who I am , child ?
You think
if I wasn 't here
your friends who cause disaster
who are stupid enough to commit sins
won 't bring harm to my granddaughter ?
I won 't let my granddaughter be harmed
by anyone here .
Do you understand , child ?
What do you mean by " harm " , Mbah ?
Pretty child .
Two of your friends will not stay alive
if they don 't stop committing sins .
Listen to me .
Tell them
before they fall even deeper .
They have crossed the line
that will make the situation worse .
They might cause harm to the whole village .
Nur !
I 'm scared , Nur .
I have failed to look after you , Widya .
I failed .
Tell me .
What are you trying to do ?
Tell me everything now .
I don 't understand .
What are you saying ?
In Widya 's bag , I found the Bangle .
I also found a green shawl in your bag .
You put the Bangle inside Widya 's bag , didn 't you ?
Where did you get that shawl ?
You stepped over the line , Nur .
Why were you going through my stuff ?
- That shawl is mine . - The Bangle is from Bima , isn 't it ?
Bima got it after a dream .
And do you know who was in his dream ?
She was a jinn , Ayu !
Where did you get that shawl ?
From the same jinn !
Come with me to Mr. Prabu 's house . You have to tell him everything .
Alright ! Alright !
I put the Bangle in Widya 's bag . Not because Bima told me to .
Then who ?
Bima did ask me to give it to Widya .
But I didn 't do it .
And then a dancer came to me .
She told me to give it to Widya .
In exchange
she gave me a green shawl that could make Bima fall for me .
You 're crazy !
You made a deal with a jinn !
Meet me at the house .
I need to talk to all of you .
Let 's go home .
Our extracurricular activities here ends tonight .
Why ?
Why can 't we finish it first ?
Ayu . Why are you crying ?
I know I made a mistake , Nur .
But I 'm begging you , Nur .
We have to finish this extracurricular activities , Nur .
- It 's not fair to the others . - We all could be in grave danger , Bima .
There 's something wrong with this place .
Why are you crying , Ayu ?
- You chose this place ! - It 's not this place 's fault !
It 's our fault !
So we 're going back tomorrow , Nur ?
Bima !
Bima ?
You 're the Dawuh that I 've been waiting for .
I love your scent .
Stay here , child .
Stay here , child !
Stay !
Ayu .
Wake up . Widya is gone .
Ayu ?
Ayu .
Ayu !
Ayu , wake up !
Help ! Help !
What is it , Nur ? What the hell ?
Widya is gone . And I found Ayu in this state !
Let 's get Mr. Prabu !
- Where is Bima ? Have you seen him ? - I don 't know .
Ayu , wake up ! Wake up , Ayu !
Ayu !
- Bring Mbah Buyut here now ! - Yes , sir !
Sir .
There 's something I need to tell you .
Ayu and Bima had sex at Tapak Tilas .
God , no .
But Bima wasn 't his normal self .
They followed everything the jinn said .
Her name is Dawuh .
I know my friends made a mistake , sir .
We made a mistake .
But I 'm begging you to save Bima and Ayu .
You , stupid ! Why didn 't you tell us earlier ?
Damnit ! How could they have sex here !
That 's enough !
Your friends are in danger !
Now ! Everyone , search !
Bima ! Widya !
Bima !
Do you know what these are ?
Both belong to the Dancer ...
The Goddess of this village .
Dawuh .
Dawuh
is not a name .
That 's the title
given to the dancer .
Her name
is Badarawuhi .
This Bangle
can only be worn
by the Dawuh that she has chosen .
This green shawl
is used to captivate anyone
that she wants .
What 's going to happen with my friends ?
I 'm begging you , please save them .
Their souls
are in Angkaramurka now .
- Forgive us , God . - I can only hope she will let them go .
Wait here .
Slowly .
Slowly , sir .
Careful .
Move .
Slowly .
Oh , God .
Widya .
I followed Bima , Nur .
I saw him there with the dancer .
They were surrounded by so many snakes .
Ayu was there too .
She was in tears .
She was forced to dance .
She was helpless .
Stop .
The souls of your friends
are trapped in Angkaramurka .
The snakes that you saw
are the offspring of Bima and Badarawuhi .
And Ayu
has been made the new Dawuh .
She has to keep dancing
every inch of the land in these woods .
They 're punished
for what they did .
For that matter ,
I can 't help you .
I 'm sorry , child .
I have failed to protect them .
A long time ago
our ancestors believed
that by sacrificing our daughters
our village would be safe from misfortune .
The gravestones covered in black cloth
are graves of those who were sacrificed
when this village was still under the devil 's temptations .
The gamelan hall at Tapak Tilas
was a venue for dance performances .
Not for our villagers
but for the spirits that inhabit the village .
I have failed to protect you all .
It 's my fault , sir .
I have failed to keep your trust .
Nur .
Let 's go home .
Goodbye , sir .
That afternoon ...
I left the village with so much guilt .
That won 't go away even until today .
BIMA DIED FOUR DAYS AFTER THEY RETURNED HOME
AYU DIED THREE MONTHS LATER
That was the last time I saw Mr. Prabu and Mbah Buyut .
We ...
never went back there .
I 'm sure Ms. Nur has asked you the same
to respect Bima and Ayu and their families ...
Please .
Do not use our real names
and do not reveal the name of that village .
- Peace be upon you . - And upon you too .
Kyai .
Do you know that someone has been looking after me ?
Her name is Mbah Dok .
She has been following you for a long time .
I have asked her to leave you before .
But she promised to look after you .
In that village
she really kept her promise .
You must feel heavy sometimes in this area .
That means that Mbah Dok
is fighting the creatures that are trying to bother you .
Peace be upon you .